原创翻译  双语字幕
《超女》前情提要
Previously on Supergirl...
最新连载海外影视剧下载
请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
仅供交流学习  禁止商用盈利
看看他们对莱克斯做的事
Look what they did to Lex.
他本可能拯救这个星球的好几代人
He could've fixed this planet for generations.
莱克斯疯了
Lex went insane.
翻译     DustD  洗七里  DerbyNinja
科拉权杖
The Staff of Koalar.
你们的神赫隆米尔的权杖是精神武器
The staff of your god H'ronmeer is a psychic weapon.
翻译     阿p  左左  C·A
我刚刚得知你拒绝在志愿者身上做试验
I was just informed that you're refusing to test my volunteers.
我和你一样希望血清尽快完成
I want this serum as quickly as you do,
校对     肉松  饿得慌
但我拒绝过早进行可能会害死特工的试验
but I refuse to rush anything that may kill your agents.
我只是需要更多时间
I just need more time.
你在哪里  曼彻斯特
Where are you, Manchester?
时间轴    想念Gallifrey的Wholock  三水
今天我要以火星猎人的身份找到你
Today I find you like a Manhunter.
后期     你是不是饿得慌
大都会
四年前
总监     你是不是饿得慌
"不论其他因素
"Against other things,
想要保证安全是有可能的
it is possible to obtain security,
但是说到死亡
but when it comes to death,
我们人类都生活在无墙的城市中"
we human beings all live in an unwalled city."
你知道这是谁说的吗
Do you know who said that?
求你了  莱克斯
Please, Lex,
你没必要这么做
you don't have to do this.
我做这些是为了我们
I'm doing this for us,
为了人类的未来
for the entire human race.
听听下边
Listen down below.
他们已经开始欢呼了
They're already cheering.
还有说那段话的是伊壁鸠鲁
And it was Epicurus, by the way.
一个230年前的警句
An aphorism 230 years old,
放到现在依然适用
and yet still as apt as ever.
你听起来像是个主修哲学的新生
You sound like a freshman philosophy major
而且正要杀死上百万人
and you're gonna kill millions of people.
这个世界无法在红太阳下生存
The world can't live under a red sun.
超人也不行
Neither can Superman.
你看  妹妹  我们作为人
You see, Sis, we as a people
开始变得软弱  臃肿
have become soft and fat,
与愚蠢
and stupid.
这里是大都会警局
This is the Metropolis Police Department.
投降
Surrender!
我说到哪了
Where was I?
我的天  莱克斯  你杀了他们
My God, Lex, you killed them.
想起来了  我们应该相信自己
Oh, that's right. We must put faith in ourselves,
但正相反  我们仰望着他
but instead, we look up to him,
瞪着呆滞的眼睛  认为他无所不能
with big glassy eyes because we think he's invincible.
我的职责就是让世界摆脱这种想法
It's my duty to dispel the world of that notion.
当他死后
And when he dies,
他们就会终于觉醒
they will finally wake up
看到他真实的样貌
and see him for what he really was,
一个假神
a false god.
至少他是个好人
At least he's a good man.
他不是人
He is not a man!
我才是明日之人  不是他
I was the Man of Tomorrow, not him!
不是他
Not him!
所以这都因为自负
So it's all ego, then?
不  这是科学
No, it's science.
我想看看这氪星人假冒者是否会流血
I want to see if the Kryptonian pretender can bleed.
即使是神也会死
Even gods can die.
你会看到的
You'll see.
所有人都会看到
Everyone will see.
然后  他们就会感谢我
And then, they're gonna thank me.
现今
中风啊
A stroke, huh?
你真的那么想和我见面吗
You wanted to see me in person that badly?
我还能说什么呢  妹妹
What can I say, Sis?
我想你啊
I missed you.
詹姆斯  我的天
James! Oh, my God.
詹姆斯
James.
超 女
第四季 第十五集
他们管这个叫怜悯休假
They call this a mercy furlough.
谢谢你们  警官  到这里就可以了
Thank you, Officer. That'll be all.
他们不会让我走出他们视线的
They never let me out of their sight.
就好像我会变成一条摆脱了链子的狗
As if I'd run away like a dog set loose from his leash.
你确实会
Well, you would.
我当然会了
Of course, I would.
但我不能  我全身都麻木了
But I can't. I'm numb top to bottom.
我的肠子结成一团  血流进了...
My guts are in knots, there's blood in my--
好了  够了
Okay, that's enough.
我要死了
I'm dying.
我知道
I know.
就这些吗  你知道
That's it. You know?
你只是在过去六周的
Well, you've only mentioned it at the start and the end
每一通电话开始与结束时都会提起而已
of every phone call for the last six weeks.
我不习惯被帮助
I'm not used to needing help.
这是软弱  可悲
It's weak, pathetic.
我很可悲
I'm pathetic.
你的白细胞数量已经稳定了
Your white blood cell count has stabilized.
你今天不会死
You're not gonna die today.
你要是完成了哈尔·艾尔血清  我明天也不会死
I won't die tomorrow either if you finish the Harun-El serum.
我不会用人命在未经测试的试验性药物上冒险
I'm not risking human lives on an experimental untested drug.
如果不是为了做药物的人体测试
What was the point of pulling strings to get you DEO resources
托关系给你搞来超查部的资源有什么意义
if not to test your drug on humans?
我没有要求你那么做
I didn't ask for that.
而且如果哈雷上校知道是你在背后作祟
And if Colonel Haley knew you were behind it--
她不知道  没人知道
She doesn't. No one does.
除了你托关系的那个人
Except the person whose strings you're pulling.
现在我开始怀疑你是不是想要
But now I wonder if you didn't wanna just pull up
袖手旁观看着我逐渐虚弱死去
a front-row seat to watch me wither away and die.
我又不是那个妄想杀死一个无敌之人时
I'm not the one who accidentally poisoned myself with Kryptonite
意外中了氪石毒的人
in a quixotic attempt to kill an invincible man.
我觉得十足讽刺的是
And while I do find the irony
你现在居然需要黑氪石
that you now need black Kryptonite
来治愈自己
to cure yourself just delicious,
你是我哥哥  莱克斯
you are my brother, Lex.
我确实想要救你
I do want to save you.
再说  你要是死了  还怎么
Besides, how can you pay your debt to society
来偿还欠下社会的债
if you're already dead?
这才是我妹妹
Now there's my sister.
莉娜  卢瑟先生  抱歉打扰了
Lena, Mr. Luthor, I'm sorry to interrupt--
没事  亲爱的  我来杯白咖啡
That's okay, honey. I'll take a flat white.
你可以叫我莱克斯
And you can call me Lex.
比较好写在杯子上
It's easier to write on the cup.
怎么了  伊芙
What is it, Eve?
是詹姆斯
It's James.
卡拉  感谢上帝你没事
Oh, Kara, thank God you're okay.
我听说凯特科出事了  很担心你会受牵连
I heard what happened at CatCo, and I wasn't sure.
没有别人受伤  只有詹姆斯
No one else was hurt, just James.
-他还好吗  -他们正要动手术
- Is he all right? - They're about to operate,
但是他的脊椎严重受损
but his, um, his spine was badly injured.
我们不知道会发生什么
We don't know what's gonna happen.
他在哪里
Okay, where is he?
他在楼上  但是他们说还不能探望
He's upstairs, but they said he can't have visitors yet.
我不是访客  这家医院是我开的
Well, I'm not a visitor. I own this hospital.
心里有小盒子  同志
Little boxes, comrade.
究竟发生了什么
What exactly transpired?
我只知道他在自己办公室从后方被枪击
All I know is that he was shot in his own office from behind.
他们用了空心弹  那东西...
They used a hollow-point bullet. It...
碎在里边了
splintered.
谁会做出这么可怕的事情
Who would so something so horrible?
一个没有灵魂的人
Someone without a soul.
这肯定是曼彻斯特·布莱克干的
This has to be Manchester Black.
他在游行时威胁过我
At the march, he threatened me.
发誓要伤害我和我的家人
He swore to come after me and my family,
所有我在乎的人
everyone I care about.
看来他先从詹姆斯下手了
Seems he started with James.
我们必须把他找出来
We have to find him.
留下陪詹姆斯
Stay with James.
他现在需要朋友们
He needs his friends right now.
我去找曼彻斯特  一切到此为止
I'll find Manchester. This ends today.
莉娜  发生这种事我很遗憾
Lena, I'm so sorry this is happening,
但你和我都知道现代医学的局限性
but you and I both know the limitations of modern medicine.
哪怕是最好的情况  詹姆斯也会瘫痪
I mean, even best case scenario would leave James paralyzed.
你的血清可以让他完全康复
Your serum could heal him entirely.
或杀死他
Or it can kill him.
我不能仅凭意愿召唤出大突破
I can't summon a breakthrough through sheer force of will.
那为什么每次我见你在压力下工作
Then how is it that every time I've seen you work under pressure,
都成功获得了突破
you have done exactly that?
莉娜  L公司和超查部
Lena, you have all of L-Corp,
所有的资源任由你调配
and you have the DEO at your disposal.
肯定还有你没利用的资源
I mean, there must be some resource that you're not utilizing.
有消息通知我
Keep me updated.
我找到曼彻斯特了
I found Manchester.
他做了很可怕的事  我能感觉到
He's done something terrible. I can sense it.
-我和你一起去  -好
- I'm coming with you. - All right.
你要去哪
Where are you going?
去找曼彻斯特·布莱克  他就是罪魁祸首
After Manchester Black. He's the one responsible.
注意安全  卡拉和我能看好家
Well, be safe. Kara and I can hold down the fort.
不  我
No, I, uh...
我必须去凯特科
I... I have to go to CatCo.
现在吗  詹姆斯是你最好的朋友
Now? I mean, James is your best friend.
他不在岗位上时  有人替班会让他安心
He would want to know that someone could be there if he couldn't.
-假如有什么万一呢  -我很快就回来
- What if something happens? - I'll be back soon.
这是什么地方
What is this place?
这是我父亲去世的地方
This is where my father died.
-超女  -交给我
- Supergirl! - I'm on it.
你好啊  荣恩
Hello, J'onn.
你怎会有能力做到这种事
How are you capable of this?
当你闯入我的大脑
When you broke into my mind
阻止我杀洛克伍德一伙人时
to stop me from killing the Lockwood brood,
你打开了一条通道
you opened up a motorway.
我也来去自如
It goes both ways.
所以每当你在我的脑子里胡乱窥探时
So, whenever you poke around in my mind
我也能窥探你的脑子  我也那样做了
I can poke around in yours. So, I did.
瞧瞧我找到了什么
And lookie what I found.
你们族人最强有力的武器
Your peoples most powerful weapon.
你不知道你手中的东西有多强大
You don't know what you're toying with.
可我知道
Oh, but I do.
我深深潜入你的脑海看了个遍
I dug deep into your mind. And the ground.
你们自称和平人士  火星人
You call yourself a man of peace, Martian,
但你们的神是愤怒之神
but your god was one of wrath!
你烧毁我父亲的坟墓
You burned my father's grave
就为了给我上神学课吗
to teach me a theology lesson?
你忘记了赫隆米尔的惩罚
You forget H'ronmeer's punishments.
你是个伪君子
You're a hypocrite.
醒醒吧  伙计
Wake up, man!
是时候踏上真正的正义之路了
It's time you followed the true righteous path.
憎恨正像烧毁火星那样焚烧这个世界
And we can put a stop to the hate that's burning this world up,
我们可以阻止它
just like it burned up Mars.
我们可以一起阻止它
We can stop it together.
我全都听到了
I heard everything.
荣恩  他说的"惩罚"是什么意思
J'onn, what did he mean when he said "The punishments"?
你有没有注意到
Have you ever noticed
你走到哪她的眼睛都盯着你看
that her eyes seem to follow you everywhere?
莱克斯
Lex...
莱克斯  情况比我想得更糟
Lex, it's worse than I thought.
假如我们不帮詹姆斯  他会死的
If we don't help him, James is gonna die.
你到底为什么在乎吉米
Why do you even care about Jimmy?
我以为你们已经分手了  大解脱啊
I thought you two broke up, and good riddance.
我推开詹姆斯
I pushed James away
是因为假如他发现我们有合作
because if he found out about us working together,
那会毁了我和他的感情
it would destroy our relationship.
而如今你叫我跟你合作去救他
And now, you're asking me to work with you to save him?
你说得对  十足的讽刺
You were right, the irony is delicious.
帮我完善哈伦·艾尔
Help me fix the Harun-El,
让我能救你们两个
and I can save both you and him.
我无法成功分离
I haven't been able to separate
药物有治愈功效的成分
the drug's more curative properties from its...
和超自然成分
extra-normal ones.
超能力
Super powers.
说多了听起来就不傻气了  试试看
Sounds less silly the more you say it. Try it.
致命的正是药物的超能力
Its super powers is what makes this drug so lethal.
明白吗  超能力需要被分离  限量
Okay? The powers need to be isolated and dosed out.
而你对氪石的研究经验最多
And you have more experience working with Kryptonite,
无论什么形式  远超过任何人
in all of its forms, than anyone else.
所以  求你帮帮我
So, please help me.
你信任我吗
You trust me?
我信任你的话  你会信任我吗
Would you trust me if I did?
但我需要你
But I need you,
这就够了
and that's enough.
莱克斯和莉娜·卢瑟
Lex and Lena Luthor,
协力救助超人最好的朋友
teaming up to save Superman's best pal.
母亲会怎么想
What would Mother think?
我的梦预知失败了
My dreams are failing me.
我本该预知到这件事的
I should've seen this coming.
我还算什么英雄
What good am I as a hero
我连自己挚爱的人都保护不了
if I can't even protect the people that I love?
那我的能力呢
What about my powers?
推论能力
Of deduction.
是我该预知到这件事
It should've been I that predicted this.
像游行这样的政治成功总会引起强烈抵制
A backlash always follows a political success like the march.
我的军团戒指也还在曼彻斯特手里
And Manchester is still in possession of my Legion ring.
他能靠戒指潜入凯特科而不被发现
He could use it to fly into CatCo undetected.
都怪我
I am to blame.
你们还好吗
Are you guys all right?
奥尔森先生情况稳定了
Mr. Olsen is stable.
我们成功移除了他颈椎附近的
We were able to remove a significant amount of shrapnel
相当一部分弹片
from around his cervical vertebra,
但我从未见过普通子弹造成这么大伤害
but I have never seen a normal bullet cause this much damage.
我们让他进入了药物诱导性昏迷
We've placed him in a medically-induced coma.
为了消肿  理所应当
To reduce swelling, of course.
有些重要决定要做  谁是直系亲属
There are going to be some decisions to make. Who is next of kin?
我们中  没有他的亲属
Well, there's... There's no family present,
但我可以代表直系亲属
but I can act as next of kin.
我们需要亲属来决定
We need a family member.
我是联邦特工  受过大量的医疗训练
Look, I'm FBI, and I have extensive medical training--
抱歉  没有法院允许的话
Sorry, without a court order--
我是直系亲属
I'm next of kin.
抱歉  刚下红眼航班
Sorry, I just got off a red-eye.
凯丽·奥尔森  詹姆斯的妹妹
I'm Kelly Olsen, James' sister.
你说你是联邦特工
Did you say FBI?
你是卡拉的姐姐吗
Are you Kara's sister?
是的  我是艾丽克斯
Yeah, um, I'm Alex.
很高兴终于见到你
It's nice to finally meet you.
真希望不是在这种情况下相见
I wish it was under better circumstances.
我想立刻去看詹姆斯
I'd like to see James, right away.
-没问题  -好
- Absolutely. - Okay.
这些人也都是家属
And these people are family, too.
请确保他们能探望病人
Make sure they have access.
这着实是种惊人的物质
It really is a remarkable substance.
是先在老鼠身上试验的
It started with mice.
当然  选择前灵长类动物
Sure, a supraprimate.
你就像在按照维基手册运营实验室
It's like your're running a lab out of a Wikipedia handbook.
怪不得效率如此低下
No wonder you're so behind schedule.
你一定要每时每刻都嘲讽我  激怒我吗
Are you going to taunt and provoke me the entire time?
我们从小就是这样合作过来的
This is how we've worked together ever since we were kids.
你提出一个理论  我说你错得有多离谱
You propose a theory, I tell you how wrong you are,
这样你就会做到更好
and it drives you to be better.
你把这个称为合作吗
And you call that working together?
你...
You're...
你很聪明  也很努力
You're brilliant and driven
喜欢反抗
and defiant.
一向如此  你只是需要一个供你反抗的人
Always were. You just needed someone to defy.
等等  你居然要把我的成功归到你的头上吗
Wait. Are you actually taking credit for my success?
你一直都在努力做到让我满意  一直都是
You were always driven to impress me. Always.
如果每次你向我展示你的作品时
And if I would've given you an inch,
我都给你一点小鼓励
if I would've thrown you a "Good job"
如果我对你说了"干得漂亮"
or cried out "That's wonderful"
或是喊出"太厉害了"
Every time you showed me one of your toys,
你觉得你还会像现在这样成功吗
do you think you would've been as successful as you are--
真是太不幸了
Oh, well, that's unfortunate.
给我点水
We need some water in here.
莱克斯  深呼吸
Lex, just breathe, okay?
谢谢
Thank you.
让他趴在地上舔吧
He can lap it up like a dog.
-岂有此理  -没关系  妹妹
- How dare you! - It's okay, Sis.
我习惯了
I'm used to it.
我在监狱里不是很受欢迎
I'm not very popular in prison.
我想说的是...
What I was trying to say is...
你一直
you were...
很优秀
wonderful.
你总是
You always...
让我很佩服  一直都是
wowed me. Always.
看看你  你做出了氪石
Look at you. You made Kryptonite.
连我都做不到这一点
Even I couldn't do that.
我以你为傲
I'm proud of you.
我们继续工作吧
Let's get back to work.
不然还没等癌症扩散  我就先肉麻死了
This sentimentality will kill me faster than the cancer.
赫隆米尔会以许多方式考验火星人
H'ronmeer tested the Martian people in many ways.
如果没通过考验  他们会受到惩罚
And when they failed him, they were punished.
愤怒之神
A god of wrath.
我们不能直接追踪曼彻斯特
We can't just track Manchester.
我们得用其他办法找他
We'll have to find him another way.
那些神秘符号
The sacred symbols.
你的圣经
Your Bible.
也许他们能告诉我们曼彻斯特接下来想干什么
Maybe they can tell us what Manchester is planning to do next.
这些符号讲述的都是赫隆米尔的复仇故事
The symbols are full of tales of H'ronmeer's vengeance.
他用暴力来推行道德法律的行为
When he would use violence to enforce moral law.
曼彻斯特可以用权杖
Manchester can use the Staff
一步步重现那些惩罚
to recreate the punishments, one by one.
这都是因为我让他进了我的大脑
All because I let him into my head.
这都是为了让我实施暴力
All to force me into violence.
你自己都说过  你认为曼彻斯特是一场考验
You told me yourself you thought Manchester was a test.
别让他得逞
Don't let him bait you.
我们去找他  然后阻止他
Let's find him and let's stop him.
好
Yes.
艾丽克斯  是我  我想问问詹姆斯的情况
Alex, it's me. I'm just checking in on James.
给我回电话  好吗
Call me back, okay?
伊芙  怎么了
Eve, what's wrong?
我理解你想救你病重的哥哥
I understand you wanting to save your dying brother,
无论他曾经做过什么
no matter what he did.
但现在为了救奥尔森先生
But now we're giving him full access
我们给了他全部权限
to everything in order to save Mr. Olsen.
我也很在乎詹姆斯
Look, I care about James, too.
但我希望能够确保
But I just wanna make sure that
你没有让自己的同情
you're not gonna let your sympathy
妨碍到你一直以来为之努力的事
jeopardize everything that you've been working toward.
伊芙  我比任何人都了解我哥的能力
Eve, I know what my brother's capable of more than anyone.
但我真的相信他现在唯一的阴谋就是想活着
But I truly believe his lone scheme right now is just to live.
我认为他无法想象一个没有他的世界
I don't think he can imagine the world without him in it.
好吗
Okay?
来吧  回去工作
Come on, let's get back to work.
怎么回事
What's going on?
他把你的地板弄脏了
He's making a mess of your floor.
我要让人逮捕你
I'll have you arrested!
别怪他  他不知道自己在做什么
Don't blame him. He knows not what he does.
毕竟他拿的是政府工资
He's on a government salary after all.
把钥匙给我
Give me the keys.
-你不是认真的吧  -立刻把钥匙给我
- You can't be serious. - Give me the keys now!
这是你自找的  女士
It's your funeral, lady.
伊芙
Eve.
他情况如何
How's he doing?
还在昏迷  但这意味着他还在恢复
Still unconscious but that means he's healing,
也算不错
so I'll take it.
谢谢你给我们权限
Thank you for giving us access.
詹姆斯对我们来说是全世界
James means the world to us.
当然  詹姆斯一直以来
Of course. James has always
都是大家梦寐以求的家人
been more of a "Chosen family" kind of guy.
说到这个  你妹妹呢
Speaking of, where is your sister?
我们需要帮助
We need help in here!
他出现了心力衰竭  让他们出去
He's coding. Get them out.
血压在急剧下降
Pressure's dropping.
把急救车推进来  得给他插管
Bring in the crash cart. He needs to be intubated.
你哥哥出现了内出血
Your brother's bleeding internally.
手术会对詹姆斯的脊髓产生严重威胁
Surgery poses a great risk to James' spinal cord,
但如果不做手术  他会继续失血过多
but if we don't operate, he'll continue to bleed out.
-可能会死吗  -是的
- He might die? - Correct.
-好  做手术吧  -我们这就为他做准备
- Yeah, let's do the surgery. - We'll prep him right away.
还有另外一种选择
Look, there is another option.
那个选择更好
It's a better one.
莉娜一直在跟政府研发一项实验性药物
Lena's working with the government on an experimental drug
可以完全治愈詹姆斯
that could heal James entirely.
好  但是为什么听起来好到不真实
Okay. Why does that sound too good to be true?
因为这种药物还没准备好
Because it's not ready yet.
但我跟她说了
But I spoke to her,
她说她还需要几小时才能把药物
and she said that she just needs a few more hours
调整到非致死的效果
to render the drug non-lethal.
你的意思是我们暂缓詹姆斯的手术
You're proposing that we hold off on James' surgery,
让他冒着几小时的生命危险
risking his life for hours,
等着用一种可能会害死他的药吗
only to administer a drug that might still kill him?
手术一定具有侵入性
The operation is gonna be invasive,
会对詹姆斯的身体系统造成创伤
and it's gonna be traumatic to James' entire system.
术后副作用只出现瘫痪都算幸运的了
He will be lucky if paralysis is his only after-effect.
你没见过莉娜工作的样子
You haven't seen Lena work.
我见她做过许多几乎不可能完成的任务
I have watched her do incredible and impossible things.
我明白你很信任她
I understand that you trust this woman,
但我不了解她
but I don't know her.
我只知道她和詹姆斯分手分得很伤心
All I know is that she and James had a messy break-up,
以及她的家族做了很多糟糕的事
and that her family has done some terrible things,
许多事都是对我哥哥做的
many of them to my brother.
那些事跟莉娜没有关系
Those things have nothing to do with Lena.
但也并不代表我愿意将自己哥哥的生命
That doesn't mean I'm willing to put my brother's life
交到她手上
in her hands.
我只希望詹姆斯得到最好的治疗
I just want what's best for James.
我也是
So do I.
心率92  还在上升
BPM's 92 and rising.
家教的名字叫什么
What was that tutor's name?
-克里尼克  -对  想起来了
- Krinick. - Yes. Yes, that's right.
现在就注射
Okay, injecting now.
如果我错误地引用了萨卢塔蒂的话
If I misquoted my Salutati,
心率124并上升
124 and rising,
她会让我站在角落用完美的拉丁语
she would make me stand in a corner and repeat,
不停地说  "我不喜欢自己"
"I do not like myself" in perfect Latin.
难怪你变成了一个反社会者
No wonder you became a sociopath.
如果适合用拉丁语来说的话
If the Latin fits.
心率143并上升
143 and rising.
把注射的药物抽回来一滴
Pull back on the drip just a touch.
不行  上一个就是这样弄死的
No, that's how we lost the last one.
你抽的是少量  不是一滴
That was a tad, not a touch.
你那样也叫科学般的精细吗
You call that scientific?
你到底想不想要成功
Do you want this to succeed or not?
抽回一滴
Pulling back a touch.
心率165
165.
心率162
162.
心率152
152.
-降下来了  -肿瘤减小了一半
- It's dropping. - The tumor's reduced by half.
心率还是有点高
BPM's still a little high.
不  心脏还在跳动
No, the heart's still beating.
我们就要成功了
We've almost got it.
是艾丽克斯
It's Alex.
你应该接
You should take that.
艾丽克斯  詹姆斯没事吧
Alex. Is James okay?
不  卡拉
No, Kara.
詹姆斯现在有生命危险
James' life is at stake
而你却把我一个人丢在这里
and you left me here alone.
他现在又要进手术室了
And he's heading into surgery again.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
他现在有内出血
He's bleeding internally.
他妹妹希望医生做手术
And his sister wanted the doctors to operate--
等一下  凯莉也来了  到底怎么回事
Hang on. Kelly's there? What is happening?
如果你在这里  你就会知道是怎么回事
You would know if you were here.
我们都需要你在这里  卡拉
We all need you here, Kara.
他要去做一个非常危险的手术
He's headed into a very dangerous operation,
也许你永远也没机会道别
and you may never get to say goodbye.
你到底在哪
Where are you, exactly?
凯特科吗  因为我打过电话去那
CatCo? Because I-I called there,
他们说你一整天都没去过那里
and-and they said that you haven't been there all day.
我在帮荣恩查一个线索
I'm... I'm helping J'onn with a lead.
荣恩需要记者帮他对抗曼彻斯特·布莱克吗
J'onn needs a reporter to help fight Manchester Black?
你打算怎么做  去访问他吗
I mean, what-what are you gonna do exactly? Gonna interview him?
不是
No, it's not th--
手术即将开始
The operation's about to begin.
我要打电话给莉娜
I have to go call Lena.
祝你调查顺利
Good luck with your investigation.
我们就要成功了
We're so close.
而现在  非致命率达到99%
At this point, it's 99% non-lethal.
但是现在不重要了
It doesn't matter now.
詹姆斯正在做手术
James is in surgery.
那你为什么还在这里
So, why are you still here?
我现在帮不了詹姆斯
I can't help James now.
我有和你说过我的狗吗  伊格内修斯
Did I ever tell you about my dog, Ignatius?
在你来到这个家之前
Before you joined our family,
他是我最亲密的伙伴
he was my closest companion.
七岁时  我们不得不让它安乐死
And when I was seven, he had to be put down.
如果你继续拿你死去的狗和詹姆斯来做比较
If you're gonna continue to compare James to your dying dog,
我不确定我会接受你的观点
I'm not sure I'm gonna be amenable to your point.
当时我想要看着我的狗安乐死
I wanted to be there for the procedure.
但是母亲坚持要我和父亲一起出差
But Mother insisted that I go on a business trip with Father.
她认为我太多愁善感了
She thought I was being too sentimental.
那是我们的妈妈
That's our mom.
那是我妈妈
That's my mom.
和父亲一起外出
A trip with Father,
一般情况下  我会很开心
that sounds like something that ordinarily would've pleased me.
但就在这次外出中
But on this particular trip,
他带了一个女人和他一起
he brought a woman with him,
我们去哪都坚持要她一起跟着来
and insisted that she go everywhere with us.
当时我才七岁  狗狗快死了
So, here I was, seven years old, dog dying,
父亲忽略我
Father ignoring me.
你说这些事的重点在哪
Is there a point to this story?
首先  我发誓要憎恨这个女人
At first, I swore to loathe this woman.
在我最需要我父亲的时候
How dare she take my father
她居然从我这里把他给抢走了
from me at the moment I needed him most?
但我无法保持遵守我的承诺
But I couldn't keep my promise.
因为她人太好了
Because she was wonderful.
她对我很好
She was so kind to me.
伊格内修斯安乐死的那天  她抱着我
On the day they put Ignatius down, she embraced me,
给我唱那首优美的爱尔兰歌
and sang me this beautiful Irish song.
出差结束的时候
By the end of the trip,
我希望她是我一个人的母亲
I wished that she was my mother.
不是你的母亲
But she wasn't your mother.
但她是你母亲
She was yours.
我要你明确地知道
I want you to know with certainty
我成长的环境是恨
that while I came from poison,
你成长的环境是爱
you came from love.
如果这个家里其余的人坚定地站在黑暗中
And if the rest of this family stands steadily in darkness,
但你总是会坠入光明中
you will always fall into the light.
见到她的那一刻我就知道
I knew that from the moment I met her.
吉米现在需要你  莉娜
Jimmy needs you now, Lena.
是詹姆斯
It's James.
你可以叫守卫进来了
You can send the guard back in.
父亲
听我说
我迷失了
荣恩
J'onn.
卡拉  艾丽克斯怎么样
Kara, how is Alex...
死了  和我一样
Dead, like me.
你袖手旁观  荣恩
You stood idly by, J'onn.
无动于衷
You just sat there,
等着
and you waited.
祈祷
And you prayed.
无动于衷
And you just sat there.
而他们却来伤害我们
While they came for us!
你们不是真的
You're not real.
-我们是  -很真实
- We are. - So real.
曼彻斯特  出来
Manchester, show yourself!
我们就是你无法拯救的人
We're the ones you couldn't save.
你不会拯救的人
Who you wouldn't save.
正如你的亲生女儿一样
Just like your own daughters!
艾丽克斯  不要
Alex! No!
艾丽克斯
Alex!
卡拉
Kara!
不
No!
荣恩  荣恩
J'onn? J'onn?
荣恩  我在这里
J'onn! Hey! Hey, I'm here.
是我  你没事了  安全了
It's me. You're okay, you're safe.
曼彻斯特想让我见识如果我继续袖手旁观
Manchester was trying to show me what could happen
事情会变成什么样
if I continue to sit idly by.
我丢下你和艾丽克斯独自面对危险
I have left you and Alex alone to face dangers.
如果我要失去我在乎的每一个人
Is choosing the path of peace worth it
那选择和平的道路还值得吗
if it means I could lose everyone I care about?
氪星毁灭后
After what happened on Krypton,
我妈妈那样袖手旁观
the way my mom stood by and did nothing,
我一直发誓如果我能做点什么  我一定会的
I've always sworn that if I can act, I will.
直到你发誓不再动武
But until you took your vow of peace,
我才明白
I didn't truly understand
仅仅是与一个人
that simply by standing
站在统一战线  就能让他更勇敢
with someone you can make them feel braver.
荣恩  我和艾丽克斯能勇敢面对危险
J'onn, the only reason Alex and I can face danger the way we do
都是因为有你的支持
is because we know you're standing by us.
任何形式的支持
In whatever way you choose.
谢谢
Thank you.
我们现在怎么做
What should we do now?
显然  曼彻斯特想让你去跟踪他
Well, clearly, Manchester wants you to hunt him,
他就可以利用你的心灵感应来攻击你
so he can exploit your psychic connection and attack you,
而我们正好落入他的圈套
and we've just been playing into his hands.
所以现在最好的办法就是
So, maybe the best thing to do now
让他来找我们
is let him come to us.
这个送你  和解礼物
It's a peace offering.
之前的事对不起  我过分了
I'm sorry about before. I was out of line.
你关心詹姆斯
You care about James.
没什么好道歉的
That's nothing to apologize for.
我收下了
But I will take it.
好  谢谢了
Yes. Thanks.
果冻太适合做医院的食物了
Oh. Jell-O really is the perfect hospital food.
这就是创伤的隐喻
It's a metaphor for trauma.
抖它一下  它就摇摆
If you shake it, it wobbles,
但还能保持原状
but it still holds its form.
如果你挖得太深  那就再也不能恢复原样了
If you dig in too deep, it's never the same.
就情况来看  你似乎
You don't seem to be wobbling very much,
也没有很摇摆不定
given the circumstances.
-在军队工作吗  -对  我是心理学家
- Military? - Psychologist, yeah.
很多事情我都见多不怪了
I have pretty much seen it all.
而且  这是第十二次
Plus, this is the 12th time
到医院来看望詹姆斯了
that I have visited James in the hospital.
你知道的  我弟弟
You know my brother,
总是到处
he's always running off
参与危险的事情
and diving into something dangerous.
家里情况不如意的时候
It was the way he coped when things
他就这么解决问题
got hard at home.
如果你一直奔跑  就不用停下来
If you just keep running then you don't have to stop
感受自己的痛苦了
and feel how much you're hurting.
这话好耳熟
That sounds familiar.
-卡拉  -嘿
- Kara! - Hi.
好久不见
Oh, it's been forever.
抱歉这么晚才来
Sorry it took me so long to get here.
你去了需要你的地方
You were where you needed to be.
现在也是
I am now.
我要去再找点零食来
I am going to go and find more snacks.
我跟你一起
Yeah, I'll come with you.
-行啊  -我叫荣恩
- Okay, cool. - J'onn, by the way.
好名字
Oh, cool name.
-法国名吗  -有点接近了
- French? - Close.
你来了
So, you came.
是的  我还准备了一堆借口
I did, and I brought a whole bunch of excuses with me.
但其实  我可能只是...
But deep down, I think I just...
不想袖手旁观
couldn't bear standing by doing nothing.
感到恐惧  无助
It's scary, feeling helpless.
这感觉很可怕
It's terrifying.
但跟你一块在这里不是没有意义的
But being here with you isn't nothing.
这意味着一切
It's everything.
过来吧
Come here.
卡拉  艾丽克斯
Kara, Alex.
他在哪里
Where is he?
-他在这边  -对  这边
- He's this way. - Yeah, this way.
好
Okay.
你还好吧
Are you okay?
我要是能拿出这巧克力  可能会好点
I would be better if I could just get a Choco!
我向来对付机器都没问题的
I usually get along so well with machines.
他会没事的
He's gonna be okay.
不只是詹姆斯
It's not just James.
就在几个月前  超女差点死了
Only months ago, Supergirl nearly died.
也不用我说
And don't even get me started
那块差点让我放弃自己的
on the AI plate that has forced me to...
人工智能板了吧
just give up my entire existence!
我告诉过你没有  我祖上世世代代都是恶人
Have I mentioned that every single one of my ancestors is evil?
还有蒙·艾尔
And Mon-El, well,
他向来都有点瞧不起人
he was always a bit dismissive.
微冒犯是他们自身创伤的一种
Microaggressions are their own form of trauma.
我...
I'm...
抱歉  我觉得...
I'm sorry. I think...
我觉得这事逼着我
I think this event has forced me to process
重新面对我以前所经历过的一切困难
every difficult thing I have ever experienced.
而我还是连巧克力都拿不出来
And I still can't even get a Choco--
功率骤增
Power surge?
曼彻斯特在水坝那里
Manchester's at the dam.
整个城市都由它供电
It powers the whole city.
他的权杖能把整个水坝毁掉
With the Staff, he can wipe it out.
我们走
Let's go.
詹姆斯  他还在做手术
James! He's in the middle of surgery!
备用发电器在哪里
Where are the backup generators?
现在本该启动了
Should be on right now.
没电就不能完成手术  他会失血过多的
We can't finish without power. He'll bleed out.
曼彻斯特
Manchester!
好了  是时候了
Well, well, it's about time.
来拿啊  和平火星人
Come and get it, Martian of peace!
水坝崩裂了
The dam's cracked.
他要淹没整个城市
He's gonna flood the whole city.
你去吧  这是我和他的战斗
Go. This war is mine.
我做了安全的选择
I picked the safe option.
既然做了安全的选择  这就不应该发生
This isn't supposed to happen when you pick the safe option.
凯丽  听着
Kelly, look, no one
没人能想到会发生这种事的
could've predicted that this was gonna happen.
你为你弟弟做了最好的决定
You made the best decision that you could for your brother,
莉娜的药那时候还不能用  现在可以了
and Lena's drug wasn't ready then. But it's ready now.
听着  我知道
Now, look, I know you have
你有充分的理由不相信莉娜·卢瑟
1,000 reasons to not trust Lena Luthor,
但我不是请你相信她
but I'm not asking you to trust her.
我请你相信我
I'm asking that you trust me.
-就这么做吧  -好
- Let's do it. - Okay.
抱歉  我不是故意偷听的
Hi. Sorry, didn't mean to eavesdrop,
坏习惯而已  但我听见你们说的了
nasty habit, but I heard what you just said.
我把药带来了  以防万一
I brought the drug, just in case.
我们现在要找到莉娜
We have to find Lena now.
该死
Damn it!
别发疯了
Stop this madness!
你会害死成千上万的人
You'll kill thousands of innocent people.
这个世界已经四分五裂了
This world is already tearing itself apart.
如果你想阻止这局面  就不要和我作对
If you want to stop that, don't fight me.
加入我
Join me.
不可能
Never.
我要做的事情完全是违法的
What I'm about to do is absolutely illegal.
任何目击者都会成为共犯
Any witnesses will be considered accessories to a crime.
-卢瑟小姐  -再不走我就解雇你了
- Miss Luthor. - Leave now before I fire you.
如果你不起来战斗  就会失去一切
If you don't stand up and fight, you'll lose everything.
又一次失去
Again.
金姆
K'hym.
塔尼娅
T'ania.
不要
No.
跑  快跑
Run. Run!
不  不
No. No!
你真漂亮
You're beautiful.
荣恩
J'onn.
曼彻斯特在哪里
Where's Manchester?
我们去看看詹姆斯
Let's go see James.
我就挨了一枪  你不用大老远地赶来
I only got shot once. You didn't have to come all this way.
你从没邀请我过来
Aw, you never invite me to visit.
不然我怎么认识你的朋友们
How else was I gonna meet your friends?
顺便说一句  他们都很好
They're pretty great, by the way.
其中一个还救了你一命
One of them even saved your life.
关于那点
Yeah, about that...
-谢谢你  -你没事就好
- Thank you. - I'm just glad you're okay.
再说了  是超女找到你的
Besides, Supergirl was the one that found you.
你该感谢她
You should be thanking her.
是的
Yeah.
我知道你刚刚死里逃生
Oh. I know you just came back from the dead,
但你会宁愿你没有  因为我刚给妈妈打了电话
but you're about to wish that you didn't because I called Mom.
我们该退场了
I think that's our cue.
不  别留下我一个人  各位
No, she... Don't leave me alone. Guys.
-祝你好运  亲爱的  -你们一直都陪着我
- Good luck, honey. - You've been there for me.
妈妈
Hey, Mom.
你应该把戒指还给布莱尼
You should give that ring back to Brainy.
他会很高兴的
He'll be happy to see it.
我还没准备好怎样解释我得到了它
I'm not ready to explain how I got it.
詹姆斯平安了
James is okay.
整个城市也平安无事
The whole city is okay
都是因为你
because of you.
是  但代价是什么呢
Yeah, but at what cost?
曼彻斯特死了
Manchester is dead.
我知道你想遵循你父亲的准则
I know you're trying to follow your father's code,
但是今天发生的一切不会改变你的为人
but what happened today doesn't change who you're trying to be.
但是我都不知道那是谁了  卡拉
But I don't know who that is, Kara.
我知道一件事
One thing I do know,
那就是我不是个爱好和平的人了
I am not a man of peace.
恕我冒昧
If I may...
-我们不需要谈论这个  -我必须说
- We don't need to talk about it. - I must.
即使这很伤人
Even if it hurts.
一位智者曾经说过
A wise man once said,
"通过深刻的经历所产生的感情
"Relationships based on intense experiences
是不会有结果的"
never work."
你在...
What are you...
这位智者是基努·里维斯
The wise man is Keanu Reeves.
说真理的人都一样
A truth-teller is there, ever was one.
尽管难以承认  你和我
It pains me to say, you and I...
我们永远无法在一起
we can never be together.
好吧  如果基努·里维斯说
All right, well, if Keanu Reeves says--
别说了  这只会让事情更加困难
Don't speak. It only makes this more difficult.
随便你怎么说  野猫
Whatever you say, wildcat.
大多数坏孩子会用放大镜烧蚂蚁
You know, most bad kids burn ants using a magnifying glass.
但你不会
But not you.
不  你会用泥巴和树枝
No, you would build ant hills
建造蚁丘  便于蚂蚁攀爬
out of mud and twigs, to scale.
这会花费你几个小时  有时几天
It would take you hours, sometimes days.
然后  你会欺骗蚂蚁
And then, you would trick
让它们以为自己回家了
the ants into thinking they were going home.
他们会沿着你布置的迷宫前进
They would follow the maze you laid out
径直地走进一团明火
and walk right into an open flame.
对不起  你到底是在指责我什么
I'm sorry, exactly what are you accusing me of?
医院断电不是因为
The power in the hospital didn't go off
大坝受到攻击
because of the attack on the dam.
是你干的
You did that.
我知道是因为
And I know because the
L公司基金会的名字刻在了这里的每一把手术刀
L-Corp foundation has its name on every scalpel,
每一个工作台和备用发电机上
bench, and backup generator in the place.
你真的变成了一个慈善家
Hmm. Quite the philanthropist you've become.
还有孩子住在这家医院  莱克斯
There were children in that hospital, Lex.
你利用对大坝的攻击来切断电源
You took advantage of the attack on the dam to kill the power,
与此同时  詹姆斯还躺在手术台上
while James was on the operating table.
你拿他和无数人的生命冒险
You risked his life and the lives of countless others
只为了逼我去测试哈伦·艾尔
just so I would be forced to test the Harun-El.
你都知道了
Aw, you figured it all out.
知道了大部分  但你漏掉了一件大事
Well, mostly. You missed one big thing.
对  关于我母亲的故事
Yeah, the story about my mother
只不过是另一个为了操控我的谎言
was just another lie to manipulate me.
不  那是真的
No, that was true.
所以它才会如此有效
That's what made it so effective.
但也是我射伤了吉米
But I also had Jimmy shot.
不幸的是  这并不像我希望的那样有效
Unfortunately, that wasn't as effective a cattle prod as I'd hoped.
你有病
You are sick.
没错
Exactly.
我快死了
I'm dying.
这个可怕的癌症正在吞噬我
This horrible cancer is eating me up
而你却还在拖延我的解药
and you are sitting pretty on the very thing that could cure me,
你甚至都不愿去测试它
and you wouldn't even test it!
上帝知道我不会
God knows I'm not going to
在自己身上测试这种实验性的致命药物
test an experimental, lethal drug on myself,
所以你需要一个由头和一只小白鼠
so you needed a nudge, and a test dummy.
它有用了
Well, it worked.
詹姆斯会活下来  而你会腐烂
James is gonna live, and you're gonna rot.
因为我绝不会
'Cause I will never,
绝不会给你解药
never give you the cure.
带他走
Take him away.
莉娜  莉娜
Lena... Lena, I...
我对你的反应很失望  但我并不惊讶
I'm disappointed that this is your reaction, but I'm not surprised.
所以十分钟前我让人给了我解药
Which is why I had someone give me the cure ten minutes ago.
-你死了  -不  是你死了
- You're dead. - No, you're dead.
不不不
No. No. No!
形象诱发器  我不得不说我之前不确定
Image inducers. I have to say, I was skeptical,
但它们确实派上了用场
but they really do come in handy.
泰斯马克女士
Miss Tessmacher!
伊芙
Eve.
抱歉  毫无愧疚
Sorry, not sorry.
-多久了  -从头到尾
- How long? - Forever.
这不关私人恩怨
It's nothing personal.
求救  求救  有人
Mayday, Mayday. Individual one--
不需要这样  泰斯马克女士
Mmm. That won't be necessary, Miss Tessmacher.
或许我妹妹希望我死
My sister may be happy to let me die,
但我不打算杀了她
but I have no intention of killing her.
你确定吗  老大
Are you sure about that, boss?
她是真的很难搞
She's a real smarty two-shoes.
就像卡在牙缝的食物
It's like food in your teeth.
总有一天你会感谢我
You're gonna thank me one day.
所有人都会  我保证
Everyone will. I'm sure of it.
待在这里  看看她
Stay here and take care of her.
好的  卢瑟先生
Yes, Mr. Luthor.
别动
Freeze! Don't move.
确实不该动
Indeed.
超女
Supergirl.
很高兴终于与你见面了
Nice to finally meet you.